埃及
人口  八千五百萬
美軍護航機疾控中心小隊
U.S. military escort CDC team
請求允許進入埃及領空
requesting permission to enter Egyptian airspace.
批準
Permission granted.
斯科特博士  從你右邊看一下
Dr. Scott, on to the right. Take a look.
他過來了
He's on approach.
能見度  很好  接近目標時間  三分鐘
Visibility -- good. Time to target -- three minutes.
收到  航向220
Roger that. 2-2-0.
收到  我看見了
Roger that. I see it.
狀態  正常
Status -- green.
斯科特博士  準備著陸
Dr. Scott, prepare for landing.
在海軍軍醫附近著陸
Putting down close to DOC.
20英尺
20 feet.
10英尺
10 feet.
著陸成功
And we're down.
博士  你有五分鐘時間
Doctor, you've got five minutes.
走這邊
This way.
在這個營地有六千名被隔離的病人
There are 6,000 quarantined in this camp.
已經死亡387個
We have 387 dead.
我的人只剩下六個了
My staff is down to six!
我覺得你該多帶點醫生來
I thought you were bringing more doctors with you.
這些是剛被染上病毒的人
These are the latest to come down with the virus.
一旦出線潰斑  兩天內就會死亡
Once the spots come, they die in two days.
疾控中心
對不起
I'm sorry.
美國海軍基地
諾福克市  弗吉尼亞州
美國內森·詹姆斯號導彈驅逐艦(151)
海軍之矛
確保這些雪上摩托都放入右舷F機庫
Make sure those snowmobiles go to starboard hangar "F"!
斯珀林和劉易斯指揮官  我們一點出發
Chief Spurling, Chief Lewis, we are getting under way at 1300.
美國內森·詹姆斯號導彈驅逐艦(151)
海軍之矛
動作快點  好嗎
Let's pick up the pace, okay?!
是  我知道關于海軍山地作戰部隊的一切
Yeah, I know all about the Naval mountain warfare unit,
但是我從未聽說過讓狗上驅逐艦的
but I've never heard of a dog setting foot on a destroyer.
這不僅僅是只狗  這可是海軍上將海爾賽
This isn't just a dog. This is Admiral Halsey.
它可是個能手
And he's a mean operator.
是嗎  艦長也是
Yeah? Well, so is the Captain.
疾控中心  易碎
美國內森·詹姆斯號
海軍基地  諾福克市
2號碼頭
實驗設備
小心輕放
你就放在那邊吧
You can just put that down over there.
小心點  那可是很精密的設備
Be careful. That's delicate equipment.
我猜你就是我的新船客
I take it you're my new houseguest.
我是指揮官錢德勒  這里的艦長
I'm Commander Chandler, ship's Captain.
蕾切爾·斯科特
Rachel Scott.
不好意思  我們借用了你們的直升機間
I'm sorry we had to take over your helicopter bay,
但這是唯一夠大能當我們實驗室的地方
but it was the only space large enough to accommodate our lab.
我船上有217男性和女性
I got 217 men and women on this ship.
有什么我該擔心的嗎
Anything I should be concerned about?
這個
Oh, this?
這只是為了防止污染試驗品
This is just so we don't contaminate the work...
沒別的意思
Not the other way around.
你們到目的地之后要研究什么
What exactly are you gonna be studying up there?
鳥
Birds.
Birds?
我們是病毒學家
We are virologists --
追蹤人跡罕至之處的隱匿微生物
Tracking obscure microbes in hard-to-get-to places.
相當無聊的工作
Pretty boring stuff, actually.
錢德勒艦長  我們非常感謝你的幫助
We really do appreciate your assistance, Captain Chandler.
愿為你服務
We're here to serve.
歡迎上船  博士
Welcome aboard, doctor.
四個月之后
最高機密  三角洲任務
阿爾法一號電磁靜默
無線電靜默
收到  甲板
Roger that. Red deck.
飛機已經固定好  準備回機庫
Bird's chocked and chained, heading to the barn.
媽的  真冷  我臉都沒知覺了
Damn, it's cold. I can't feel my face.
格蘭德森上尉  快告訴我  我的臉還在嗎
Lieutenant Granderson, tell me -- do I still have my face?
在  長官  不過看起來你該用點唇膏
Yes, Sir,though it looks like you could use some lip balm,Sir.
我真該去邁阿密做文職的
Should've taken that desk job in Miami.
太冷了
It is cold!
艦長在艦橋上
Captain's on the bridge!
斯萊特里大副
X.O. Slattery,
我們來試試  能不能把你的凍屁股帶回諾福克市
let's see if we can get your frozen ass back to Norfolk.
-作戰官  艦橋來電  -艦橋  我是作戰官
- T.A.O., Bridge. - Bridge, T.A.O.
直升機剛為最后的導彈測試釋放了目標
Our helo just dropped a target for our final missile test.
目標物五英尺長  兩英尺寬
Target's five feet long, two feet wide,
而且在冰水中沒有熱成像
and in the icy water has no heat signature.
找到目標消滅它
Let's find it and kill it.
掃描目標中
Scanning for target.
掃描區域
Scanning zone.
攻擊軌跡5205  目標已獲取
Kill track 5205.Target acquired.
目標已獲取  完畢
Target acquired. Break.
攻擊軌跡0845  明白
Kill track 0845, aye.
多光譜掃描儀  攻擊軌跡0845
Mss, kill track 0845.
導彈準備點火
Missile ready to fire.
導彈發射  航向220  高度30
Missile clear. 2-2-0, 30.
距離三萬英尺
30,000.
爆炸范圍
目標清除
Target confirmed kill.
下午好  內森·詹姆斯號  我是艦長
Good afternoon Nathan James. This is the Captain.
在世界之巔經歷了四個月的艱巨挑戰
After four very challenging months at the top of the world,
我們剛通過了終極測試
we have just passed our final test,
我很自豪地說你們完成的相當出色
and I'm proud to say you did it with flying colors.
我問問國防部今天能否取消無線電靜默
I'm asking the Pentagon if we can break radio silence today
打打電話  發發郵件
and make calls and e-mail.
向你們所有人表示祝賀
Bravo zulu to each and every one of you.
享受你們的勝利吧  因為我們要回家了
Enjoy your success, 'cause we're going home.
溫度即將降至零下50度  叫他們從冰原回來
Gonna drop to 50 below. Get them off the ice.
是  長官
Aye, sir.
斯科特博士  快回來
Dr. Scott, come in.
斯科特博士  聽到了嗎
Dr. Scott, are you there?
請回答
Please respond.
斯科特博士  進來
Dr. Scott, come in.
你們是在逗我吧
You have got to be kidding me.
我們就要成功了
We're so close.
我們得確保隔離病毒沒有被污染
We need to make sure the isolate isn't contaminated.
我們需要更多樣本
We need more samples.
沒事的  蕾切爾  我們可以明天再來
It's all right, Rachel. We can come back tomorrow.
女士  我們一直在試圖聯系你
Ma'am, we've been trying to reach you.
指揮官想讓你回船上去
C.O. wants you back on the ship.
你告訴艦長我準備好了就會回去
You can tell the captain that I'll return when I'm ready.
這可不是邀請  女士
It wasn't an invitation, ma'am.
現在就回去  艦長的命令
Right now. Captain's orders.
著陸準備已完成  起落架放下鎖定
Landing check is complete. Gear down and locked.
20英尺
20 feet.
10英尺
10 feet.
著陸
Wheels down.
我們抓緊時間  還能趕回去比賽
We haul ass from here, we can make it back for the series.
你不會真的以為那幫菜鳥還有贏的希望吧
You don't really think the cubs are still in it.
這是棒球聯賽里最弱的分區
It's the weakest division in baseball.
我們離開時打贏了六場比賽
We were six games up when we left.
那是六月的事  他們都是新人
Yeah, that was June. And they're the cubs.
錢德勒艦長  你沒權利不讓我工作
Captain Chandler, you had no right to pull me from my work.
-我要去看看...  -好的
- I'm gonna go check on the, uh... - yeah.
他們來這里是為了支持我工作
Those men are here to support me.
你不能派他們帶我回來
You don't send them to bring me in.
那些人是美國海軍的船員
Those men are sailors in the U.S. navy
-直接向我匯報  -等我弄完準備好就回來
- and report directly to me. - I say when I am done and ready.
我的工作至關重要  我終于找到了
My work is vital here, and I have finally found
-一直在尋找的東西  -博士
- what I'm looking for! - Doctor!
首先  謝謝你上船
First of all, thanks for checking in.
這是我們離開諾福克后  你頭一次跟我說話
Think this is the first time you said more than three words
超過三個詞
to me since we left Norfolk.
那我很抱歉沒請你喝茶
Well, I am sorry that I haven't had you over for tea.
六月在維吉尼亞州那會兒你的態度還算迷人
You know, your attitude was mildly charming back in June in Virginia
但在這里  零下五十度
but up here, at 50 below,
四個月來沒人提起過家人
when none of us have talked to our families in four months,
你就沒那么迷人了
not so charming.
-實際上魅力并不是我的  -還說呢
- Yeah, well, charm wasn't exactly my pri-- - Still talking.
現在  我覺得我不僅是位和藹可親的船主
Now, I think I've been more than a gracious host --
載你和你的助手到這里的島嶼
taxied you and your assistant around the islands here
讓你能夠追逐你的鴨群們
so you could chase after your ducks.
-那是北極燕鷗  -你得收工了
- Arctic terns. - You need to wrap it up.
我們的任務已經完成  就要返航了
Our mission's done, and we'll be heading back.
喝茶的事先延期吧
I'll take a rain check on the tea.
本佐  吃點水果
Benzo, eat some fruit.
拜托  鐘先生
Come on, Mr. Chung.
這是我們在北極待得最后一晚了
It's our last night at the North Pole.
我知道你有好些遠大的計劃
Look, I know you've got big plans,
但你就沒有不看書的時候嗎
but don't you ever get your head out of that book?
沒有
Nope.
好吧
Okay.
上尉
Lieutenant.
丹尼
Danny, whoa.
別這樣
Don't do that.
哪樣
Do what?
你知道那樣的笑容會誘惑到我
You know what that smile does to me.
情場如戰場
All's fair in love and war.
是啊
Yeah.
卡拉
Kara...
我們很快就回家了
We'll be home soon enough.
你們在聽我說嗎
Hello. Are you reading me?
快點
Come in.
請勿觸碰
不行  我等不了
No, I cannot wait.
我是蕾切爾·斯科特
This is Dr. Rachel Scott.
我現在就要跟國家安全顧問通話
I need to speak to the National Security Adviser right away.
你不明白  我的任務被連累了
You don't understand. My mission is being compromised.
我需要更多時間來采集樣本
And I need more time to collect samples.
頻道信號不好  重復一遍
We have a noisy channel. I repeat.
任務目標已實現  我們準備回家  完畢
Mission objectives achieved. We are ready to come home. Over.
不行  指揮官
That's a negative, commander.
任務已經拓展  完畢
The mission has been extended. Over.
拓展  為什么
Extended? Why?
保持無線電靜默和當前位置
Maintain radio silence and current position
直到接收到進一步的指示
until you receive further instructions.
通信中止  長官
Transmission terminated, sir.
任務拓展
第二天
那女人干嘛呢
The hell is that woman doing?
昆西
Quincy...
我覺得我們成功了
I think we've got it.
抱歉  哥們兒  我弄醒你了嗎
Sorry, man. Did I wake you?
博士讓我保持距離
Doc told me to keep my distance.
大狗正在趕鳥呢
The Admiral's scaring off the birds.
你確定是狗的動靜  不是你自己喘氣
Sure it was the dog and not your breath?
去你的
Whatever.
哥們  我們幾天之前就應該回到艦上了
Man, we should've been out of here days ago.
見鬼
What the...
航空器迫近中  方位北76.35
Aircraft in position seven six decimal three five north,
東59.58
zero five nine decimal five eight east...
艦長  發現三個
Captain, I have three
不  五個不明航空器迫近中
-- make that five unknown aircraft Approaching,
距離24海里  速度約為80節
range 24 nautical miles, approximately 80 knots.
那可不是我們的直升機
Those are not ours, man.
不是  是俄國人
No. They're Russian.
-快跑啊  -昆西  我們必須保住樣本
- Come on! - Quincy, we have to save the samples!
-來幫我  -別管什么樣本了  快跑
- Help me! - Leave the box! Let's go!
蕾切爾  別管那箱子了
Rachel, leave the box!
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
翻譯 sienna  幸田實果子  章魚X  roaddog  拉圖  圈圈
翻譯/校對  衛老哥    后期  愛卿遛小鳥
時間軸  薛定諤的貓  靈媒    總監  衛老哥
快點  快跑
Let's go! Right now!
快走啊  快啊
Let's go! Come on!
昆西
Quincy!
敵方著陸
Drop.
-啟動一級戰備狀態  -一級戰備一級戰備
- Set general quarters. - General quarters, general quarters.
全員各就各位
All hands, man your battle stations.
旋至前右側舷向上傾 艦尾左舷向下
Transit up and forward starboard side, down and aft portside.
不明航空器
Unknown aircraft...
作戰官  空中監控系統就緒
T.A.O., surface manned and ready.
攻擊艇小隊準備  近戰系統設為自動開火
Deploy SCAT. Ciws to A.A.W. auto. Hold fire on.
活捉他
Take him alive!
全速前進  左轉舵
All engines ahead flank! Hard left rudder!
全速前進  明白
All engines ahead flank, aye!
這里是美國海軍軍艦
United States naval warship.
立即說明身份并改變航向
Identify yourself and alter your course,
否則我方將采取防衛措施  完畢
Or you will be subject to defensive actions. Over.
偵測到導彈來襲
Evaluate as inbound missile.
立即發射干擾彈  有撞擊  站穩
Recommend launch chaff. Brace for shock!
所有人  站穩扶好
All hands, brace for shock.
把它們干掉
Take 'em out.
5吋炮準備開火
Go to the 5 inch!
空中監控  打擊軌道5024
Surface, T.A.O., kill track 5024.
監控收到  艦炮打擊軌道5024
Surface, aye. Guns, kill track 5024.
艦炮就緒
Guns, aye.
你還好嗎
You okay?!
-我們沒事  -來吧
- Clear! - Come on.
斯科特博士在哪
Where's dr. Scott?!
她傷情不輕
She's banged up pretty good.
醫生正在二號艙為她包扎
Doc's looking at her in hangar two.
你們是什么人
有什么企圖
回答我
他說什么
What'd he say?
解藥
"The cure."
他們想來搶解藥
He wants the cure.
我們沒有減員  現在我們和俄國開戰了嗎
All our guys are accounted for. We at war with the Russians?
聯系艦隊司令部
Get me fleet forces.
無應答的話就聯系軍事指揮中心
They don't answer, get me N.M.C.C.
再沒應答就給我聯系國防部長
They don't answer, get me Secdef.
-不是應該無線電靜默嗎  -沒必要了
- Supposed to be radio silent. - Not anymore.
我說了我沒事  麻煩你快點
I told you I'm fine. Just hurry up.
昆西在哪  我要我的樣本
Where's Quincy? I need my samples.
你若不告訴我到底怎么回事  就別想碰樣本
You don't get your samples until you tell me what's going on here.
-你無權命令我...  -所有人  出去
- You have no authority over me -- - Everybody out!
你必須馬上把那個箱子交給我
You need to hand that case over to me right now.
我們可能已經和俄國人開戰了
We may have just gone to war with Russia,
而他們顯然是沖著你來的
And they were clearly after you.
別再保密了
No more secrets.
告訴我解藥是怎么回事
Tell me about the cure!
在向國安部匯報之前
I can't say anything until I speak to the National
-我不能  -信不信老子我把樣本扔海里去
- Security -- - I swear to god, I will throw this overboard!
給我說實話
I want answers!
你想知道真相
You want answers?
七個月前  在開羅郊外  爆發了一場疫情
Seven months ago, outside Cairo, there was an outbreak --
一種來源不明的病毒
A virus of unknown origin.
其基因結構我們前所未見
Its genetic structure was like nothing any of us had ever seen.
這場瘟疫夷平了那個村
It swept throughout the village,
所有感染者都死了
killing everyone that it infected.
埃及官方宣布疫情已經得到控制
Egyptian officials claimed the outbreak was contained,
其實沒有
but it wasn't.
正相反  病毒不斷變異擴散
Instead, it continued to mutate and spread.
疾控中心和世衛組織想從患者身上
The C.D.C. and the W.H.O. wanted to sample the virus
分離病毒樣本用以制造疫苗
fom the victims to create a vaccine.
但什么用都沒有
But nothing worked.
我則相信需要從北極圈尋找到
It was my belief that we needed to find the primordial strain
病毒的源頭
here in the Arctic.
那些海鳥
The birds.
它們只是病毒攜帶者
They're just the carriers.
它們肯定在融化的凍土上沾染了病毒
They pick up the virus from the melting permafrost.
而我們總算找到了海鳥的聚食區
We finally found their feeding ground.
這么說你已經找到了治愈瘟疫的方法了
So you have what you need to stop this thing?
這只有回到實驗室進一步試驗才知道
I won't know until we get it back to the lab.
我們沒時間了
We're running out of time.
病毒在世界各地快速傳播
The virus back home is moving quicker
比我們預想的要快得多
than any of us could've imagined.
你怎么知道
How would you know that?
我們離開諾福克之后就一直無線電靜默
We've been radio silent since we left Norfolk.
因為我自備有衛星電話
Because I have my own sat phone.
我們在電磁靜默  沒人能知道我們的位置
We were at emcon so no one would know our position!
我們電磁靜默是保護我的任務
We were at emcon to protect my mission...
不是你的
not yours.
是白宮下的命令
Orders came from the White House.
你把俄國人徑直引來
Well, you led the Russians right to us
威脅了我全艦船員的安全
and endangered my entire crew.
我必須和國內的
It was imperative that I stay in contact
實驗室保持聯系  通知我們的進展
with the labs back home to keep them informed of my progress.
我覺得你還不明白我們在說什么
I don't think you understand what we're talking about here.
還請賜教
Enlighten me.
我們離開諾福克的時候
When we left Norfolk,
病毒還處于第二階段
the virus was at phase two,
僅在亞非兩洲小范圍傳播
limited to small clusters in Asia and Africa.
現在我們處于第六階段
We are now at phase six --
全球蔓延
global pandemic.
全世界八成人口已經被感染
80% of the world's population is infected.
全世界都生病了  錢德勒艦長
The world is sick, Captain Chandler...
奄奄一息
very sick.
你是告訴我全世界都不保了
Are you telling me the whole world is dying,
而他們派兩個人來拯救世界嗎
and they send two people to save it?
我說服政府把我派來都花了好幾周
It took weeks to convince the government to even send me here.
我大多數同事覺得我瘋了
Most of my colleagues think that I'm insane.
你瘋了嗎
Are you?
我說了...
I told you...
那箱子里的東西
that what's in that case...
可能是我們唯一的希望
might be the only hope that we have.
艦長  美國總統要跟您視頻通話
Captain, we have the President of the United States on the vidcom.
抱歉讓你用這種方式發現
I'm sorry you had to find out this way.
現在能把樣本給我了嗎
Can I have my samples now?
請等待總統
Stand by for the President.
早上好  中校
Morning, commander.
夫人
Ma'am?
我知道  你上次通話  我還是眾議院議長
I know. The last you heard, I was speaker of the House.
總統兩個月前去世了
The President died two months ago,
隨后一周副總統也走了
the Vice President a week later.
聯邦政府剩余的人員
What's left of the federal government
都躲避在白宮地下六十米的地方
is holed up 200 feet below the White House,
通訊也時好時壞
and communication is getting spotty.
所以我們現在想知道...
So we need to know now...
斯科特醫生找到自己做疫苗的東西了嗎
does Dr. Scott have what she needs to make a vaccine?
她覺得她找到了  夫人
She thinks so, ma'am.
我們正在向你發送坐標
We are sending you the coordinates
是座位于北卡羅來納沿岸的安全生物實驗室
to a secure bio-lab on the coast of North Carolina.
夫人  我們剛被俄國人攻擊了
Ma'am, we were just attacked by the Russians.
俄羅斯已經沒有正常運作的政府了
Russia no longer has a functioning government.
據我們所知
From what we're hearing,
一股分裂勢力在獨自運作
a breakaway force is operating on its own authority.
我們正在確定所有消息
We're trying to ascertain all the facts.
夫人  我們的家人  我們怎么能知道...
Ma'am, our families -- how do we find out if...
我也希望能告訴你  艦長
I wish I could tell you, Captain.
我國的大部分人口  包括軍隊  都在死亡
most of our population, al-- with our armed forces, is dying or dead.
我們沒有同盟
We have no allies.
也沒有敵人
We have no enemies.
只是滿世界病重絕望的人民
Just a world of sick, desperate people.
過去幾個月  你的艦只幸運地
Your ship was fortunate enough to be out of the hot zone
躲過了高危地帶
these past months.
如果斯科特醫生有疫苗配方
If Dr. Scott has the makings of a cure,
你們必須立刻趕回祖國
you have to come home...now.
供應鏈徹底斷裂
Supply chains are completely broken.
食物短缺  醫院...
Food is in short supply. Hospitals --
天朝政府對本國人民投下炸彈
...Chinese government have detonated the bomb on its own people
以阻止致命病毒傳播
to stop the spread of the deadly virus.
隨著全世界近一半人口的死亡
With possibly half the world's population dead or dying,
美國囤積疫苗的傳言甚囂塵上
rumors that the U.S is hoarding a vaccine continue to swirl.
即時新聞  倫敦大火
城市服務完全停滯
Urban services are completely overwhelmed.
在大多數城市  全城電網癱瘓
In most cities, entire power grids are down,
通訊完全中斷
making communication next to impossible.
人們紛紛質問  "政府在哪里"
People are asking, "where is the government?"
這病毒沒有治療方法  沒有預防疫苗
The virus has no treatment, no vaccine.
-所以武器測試這回事  -都是借口
- So this whole weapons test -- - It was all just a cover.
而電磁靜默
And emcon alpha --
讓我們不知道家里發生了什么
keep us in the dark about what was going on at home.
在法國沿岸有一個無人值守的加油停靠點
There's an unmanned refueling station off the coast of France.
如果我們以傳動軸推進 就應該能趕到
If we operate at trail shaft, we should just make it.
我們怎么知道他們的燃油夠我們橫跨大西洋
How do we know they have enough fuel to get us across the atlantic?
我們不知道
We don't.
我們怎么跟船員說
What do we tell the crew?
實說
Everything.
實話實說
We tell them everything.
艦長
Captain?
船員都集合了
Crew's assembled.
全體船員  立正
Ship's company, attention!
我有消息
I have news...
祖國的消息
from home.
此通訊網絡各接收站
Any station this net,
這里是內森·詹姆斯號  通過艦隊通訊衛星
this is Nathan James transmitting in the blind
一  二  三號公開發送消息  完畢
on FleetSat One, Two, and Three, over.
是否有其它艦只
Is anybody out there?
無接收信號
因大范圍系統問題
Due to widespread system failure,
您所撥打的號碼無法接通
The number you are calling cannot be reached.
此消息將無法上傳
This message will not be updated.
爸爸
Daddy!
不敢相信這么久都聽不到你的聲音
I can't believe I'm gonna go that long without hearing your voice.
我們會想你的  爸爸
We miss you, daddy.
艦長到達艦橋
Captain's on the bridge!
長官  我們距歐洲海岸50英里
Sir, we're 50 miles off the coast of Europe
可是仍然聯系不上法國海軍司令部
and still no contact with French Naval Command.
正在密切注意  武器也已就緒
We've got extra watch and guns at the ready.
能聯系上國內嗎
Were you able to reach home?
不能  長官
No, sir.
只有四人聯系到了其他人
I think only four people got through to anyone.
情況并不好
And the news wasn't good.
上次我們停靠法國海港時
Last time we made port in France,
我答應我女朋友
I promised my girlfriend
我們要一起去巴黎觀光
we'd come back and see Paris together.
這是我一直所掛念的
With everything, that's all I keep thinking about.
確實至關重要
Well, that's the stuff that matters.
大副到達艦橋
X.O.'s on the bridge.
我聯系上家人了
I got through to home.
我的兒子去世了
My boy's gone.
邁克
Oh, Mike.
克里斯汀躲在了鹿園  暫時安全
Christine is up in Deer Park, some sort of safe zone for now.
女兒們和她在一起
Girls are with her.
-要不你去休息會  我來負責  -不用
- Why don't you take a break? I-I got it. - No, no.
我不能坐在船艙對著墻發呆
I'm not gonna sit around my cabin staring at the walls.
我要留在這里
This is where I need to be.
長官  我們收到一條發射命令
Sir, we have a fire order.
所有頻道都接收到了  不過是亂碼的
It came across all channels, but it's garbled.
無法證實
They cannot authenticate.
上尉
Lieutenant?
長官  發射命令已確認  但是目標不明
Sir, confirmed fire order, but the target's unclear.
警報  警報  警報
Vampire, vampire, vampire!
導彈正從高空以高速襲來
Missile incoming high and fast.
裝填四枚戰斧導彈  等待確定目標位置
Spin four Tomahawks. Hold for a target location.
坐標位置說不通啊
These coordinates don't make any sense.
-司令部沒有回應  -電戰官收到  結束
- No response from command. - E.C.O., aye. Break.
輪機軍士長一組  校準四枚E級導彈
MM1, align four echo missiles
放入發射井內
and place them in the reload pool.
-確認目標了嗎  -現在調至5-1并且跟蹤
- Do we have a target I.D.? - Now five-one and trail.
導彈由北大西洋一艘水面艦艇發射
Missile fired from a surface ship in the North Atlantic.
彈道導彈以每小時9700英里的速度飛行
Ballistic missile traveling at 9,700 miles per hour.
已確認  即將空中核爆炸
Confirmed. We have a nuclear burn in the air.
我們無法攔截
We have no chance to intercept.
封艙
Batten down.
艦長室指揮官  封艦
Officer at the one, seal the ship.
準備迎接核爆
Prepare for nuclear detonation.
這不是演習
This is no drill.
長官  導彈從我們旁邊飛過  飛向陸地
Sir, the missile overshot us. Headed for land.
12秒后爆炸
Detonation in 12 seconds.
艦橋  護住眼睛
Bridge, shield your eyes.
老天保佑
God help us.
上報總機和發電機的狀態
Give me a status report on the switchboard and generators.
-是誰  -鐘  長官
- Who's that? - Chung, sir.
-有人受傷嗎  -沒有  長官
- Anyone hurt? - No, sir.
引擎狀態如何
What's our engine status?
長官  爆炸產生的電磁波
Sir, the, uh, electromagnetic pulse from the bomb
沖擊了電網
blew our grid.
引擎發動不了  無法推進
Engines won't spin. No propulsion.
現在只有電池給應急燈供電
Emergency lights operating on battery power.
艦長
Captain!
是你嗎  軍士長
That you, Master Chief?
電傳顯示無線電出故障了
Commo says the radios are down.
無法接收或發送信息
No way to get messages in or out.
我們得把船開出爆炸區
We need to move this ship away from the blast zone.
上尉  我們要讓引擎重新運轉
Lieutenant, let's get those engines back online.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
現在溫度多少
What temperature are we at?
41度  負壓已經丟失
41 degrees, and we've lost negative pressure.
該死  要前功盡棄了
Damn it. We're gonna lose everything.
取冰塊
Okay, get the ice.
熔斷器裝好
Fuses in.
開啟三號  四號  五號閥門
Open valves three, four, and five.
關閉輔助引擎和應急通風閥門
Shut valve to auxiliary engines and emergency air.
燃油桿準備就緒
Fuel lever on start.
好的  啟動吧
All right. Give it a kick start.
長官  只剩一個熔斷器了
Sir, we only have one more fuse.
空氣急流把所有東西向北東北方向吹去
The jet stream's pushing everything north-northeast.
輻射云馬上就要飛到我們頭上
We got a cloud of radiation about to drop right on us.
給我
Give it to me.
-長官  堅持不住的  -堅持的住
- Sir, it won't hold. - It'll hold.
-艦長  讓其他人來吧  - 啟動
- Captain, let somebody else do this. - Rip it.
-把手挪開  -我不想說第二遍
- Get your hand out of there. - You heard me.
-艦長  不要  -給我啟動
- Captain, don't. - I said rip it!
牛逼  艦長
Badass, captain.
牛逼
Badass.
所有引擎全速開動  左滿舵
All engines ahead full. Left full rudder.
保持新航向270
Steady on new course 270.
燃料余量多少
What's our fuel percentage?
11%  長官
11%, sir.
就算用最節約的模式  六小時后燃油也會耗盡
Even at max conserve, we'll run dry in six hours.
海面搜索有任何消息嗎
Any contacts on surface search?
沒有  長官  范圍30英里
No, sir. 30-mile range.
-那片雷達盲區是什么  -改變距離標尺
- What is that in the radar shadow? - Change range scale.
看起來像一艘船
Looks like a ship.
計算攔截航線
Calculate a course to intercept.
標志顯示這是一艘意大利船
Markings indicate the ship is Italian.
可以進行船間通信嗎
Bridge to bridge operational?
應該可以  長官
I think so, sir.
北48度  西14度附近船只注意
Vessel in vicinity 48 degrees north, 15 degrees west,
這里是美國海軍151戰艦  在你們右舷船首
this is U.S. Navy warship 151 on your starboard bow.
請說明你們的身份  完畢
Acknowledge and identify yourself. Over.
史密斯  羅勒  本茲  格林
Smith, Rowler, Benz, Green,
你們負責食物補給
you're on provisions.
軍士長  你協助鐘進行航行間燃料補給
Master chief, you'll assist Chung with the UNREP.
我們盡量多拿食物和燃料  然后撤出
We get as much food and fuel as we can and we get out.
出發
Let's move.
記住  如果這艘船已經被病毒侵襲
Remember, if the ship has been impacted by the virus,
因為它可以通過空氣傳播  傳染性非常高
it's airborne and highly, highly contagious,
哪怕是剛死不久的尸體也極具傳染性
even from a recently deceased corpse.
所以你們必須全程戴好面罩
You must keep your helmets on at all times.
你受過這方面訓練  你可以的
You trained for this. You can do it.
上尉  讓士兵去廚房
Lieutenant, send naval warfare to the kitchen.
盡量多拿食品和補給
Get as much food and supplies as you can.
我們去儲藏室
We got the stock rooms.
本佐和我去右舷
Benzo and I will take the starboard side,
從那里再到船上的廚房
make our way to the galley.
軍士長  把油管拉過來然后開始抽油
Master chief, get that fuel line across and pump it.
發射牽引繩
Sending the pull line.
發送輸油管
Sending over the hose.
拉繩子
Feed the line.
艦橋呼叫工程員
Engineering, bridge.
正在安裝輸油管
Engage fueling.
安裝完畢  開始抽取燃油
System online! Commence fueling!
船上安全
Ship's clear.
沒有生還者  錢德勒指揮官  完畢
No one alive, Commander Chandler. Over.
救救我
Aiutami.
斯科特博士
Dr. Scott!
救救我
Aiutami.
他在求救
He wants help.
現在唯一能幫他的就是嗎啡
The only thing that can help him now is morphine.
別管了
Let go.
我靠
Oh, shit!
弗蘭基
Frankie!
該死
Damn it.
快把面罩戴上
Put your mask on!
不  已經來不及了
No! It's off!
我靠
Oh, shit.
弗蘭基
Frankie. Hey.
弗蘭基  沒事的
Frankie! It's all right!
快起來
Look! Get up!
快走吧  哥們  快走
Get away, man. Get away!
軍士長  燃油已經快抽干了
Master chief, we're running dry here.
工程員呼叫艦橋  脫開輸油管
Engineering, bridge. Disengage.
是  長官  他們已經搞定了  小鐘
Yes, sir. They've got it, Mr. Chung.
-我們走吧  -是  長官
- Let's get out of here. - Yes, sir.
-你不會有事的  -快走
- You're gonna be fine! - Get away!
-拿好食物然后離開這里  -不
- Just take the food and go get the hell out of here. - No!
-我不會拋下你的  弗蘭基  -我已經死定了
- I'm not leaving you, frankie! - I'm a dead man.
你快走吧
Just get out of here.
不  哥們  我不會拋下你的
No, man. I'm not leaving you!
你來跟他說
You tell him.
他已經暴露了
He's been exposed.
我們讓他穿好防護服
We put him back in his suit
然后在船上隔離他
and we quarantine him on the ship!
你不能冒這個險  長官  任務第一
You can't risk it, sir. Mission comes first.
我不是很想死得像那些人一樣
I'm not all too interested in dying like these people.
把槍給我  水兵
Give me the gun, sailor.
弗蘭基  別犯傻
Frankie, don't be stupid.
我在給你下達直接命令
I am giving you a direct order!
放下武器
Put down that weapon!
弗蘭基  不要
Frankie, no!
主啊  藉您言語之威
Lord god, by the power of your word,
平息茫茫大海
you stilled the chaos of the primeval seas,
退去呼嘯洪水
made the raging waters of the flood subside,
讓加利利海風暴止息
and calmed the storm on the sea of Galilee.
我們把我們的兄弟弗蘭克林·愛德華·本茲送入海中
As we commit our brother Franklin Edward Benz to the sea,
愿他得到平靜與安寧
grant him peace and tranquility
直至弗蘭克林和所有信奉您之人
until that day when Franklin and all those who believe in you
得水的洗禮之應許
will be raised to the glory of new life
獲得榮耀新生
promised in the waters of baptism.
阿門
Amen.
向左轉
Left face!
疾控中心
設置序列號
舉槍
Present arms!
預備
Ready.
瞄準
Aim.
發射
Fire!
預備
Ready.
發射
Fire!
這些人都靠我了
These people depend on me.
我現在處于一片未知領域
I'm in uncharted territory here.
我們都一樣
We all are.
你不一樣  你知道會發生這種事
Not you. You saw this coming.
我從來沒想過會傳播這么快
I never thought it would spread so fast.
但我現在知道為什么了
But now I know why it did.
我把我們從意大利人身上采集的血樣
I compared the blood that we took from the Italian
跟我們出發前采集的樣本進行了對照
to some samples I took before we left.
病毒現在擁有一段超基因
The virus has an extra gene now,
只可能是被人為加入的
which could have only been added with human intervention.
病毒被武器化了
So it was weaponized.
也許
Maybe.
或者是從某個實驗室泄漏的
Or maybe it escaped from a lab somehow.
但我知道如何消滅它了
But I think I know how to stop it.
病毒的天性就是自我復制
All the virus cares about is replicating.
改造過的病毒能夠不受約束的復制自身
The engineered version lets it do that unchecked.
所以也就不再需要突變
So it no longer needs to mutate,
因此病毒很穩定  也就更容易被疫苗消滅
which makes it stable and easier to defeat with a vaccine.
為什么之前沒有人這么做
Then why hasn't anybody done that yet?
因為他們都沒有原始樣本
Because they didn't have the primordial sample.
我們有
We do.
艦橋指揮室  請接艦長
Bridge, commo, get me the Captain.
長官  我們終于收到電傳指令了
Sir, we finally got the comms up.
這個
This came through.
-來自總統的消息  -這已經是五天前的了
- A message from POTUS. - This is five days old.
是的長官  這是在無線電失靈的時候傳送的
Yes, sir. It was transmitted while the radios were down.
我們必須確認這些命令  給我接五角大樓
We need to confirm these orders. Get me the pentagon.
長官  我試過了  但是沒有回復
Sir, I've -- I've been trying, but there's no answer.
我打給實驗室  給我接總統地下掩體
I'll try the lab. Get me the presidential bunker.
北卡羅來納不安全
North Carolina's not safe.
總統希望我們改變路線去梅波特
President wants us to change course for Mayport.
那邊的杰克森鎮有一間實驗室應該很安全
There's a lab in Jacksonville that's supposed to be secure.
那里和五角大樓都沒有回復
There's no answer there or the Pentagon.
長官  掩體也沒有回復
Sir, nothing from the bunker.
也許是我們的信號沒發出去
Maybe our signal's not getting out.
要不我們檢查一下發送端
We check the transmit side?
不是那個問題  他們的電話能打通
That's not the problem. Their phones are ringing.
長官  我又收到一條消息
Sir, I have another message coming through!
跟總統那條消息同時傳輸的
It was transmitted at the same time as POTUS'.
這文件看起來大得多
It looks like a much bigger file.
-是個視頻文件  長官  -播放
- It's an mpeg, sir. - Play it.
湯姆
Tom.
我們在你父親的小屋里
We're at your father's cabin.
他說他有辦法通過五角大樓的關系
He thinks he has a way to get this message out
把這段視頻傳送出去
through his contacts at the Pentagon.
我不知道你什么時候能夠看到
I have no idea when you might be seeing this
或是在哪里看到
or where you are.
我們都很健康
We're all healthy.
我們設法早早離開
We managed to get out early
已經在這里待了幾個月了
and have been up here for a couple months already.
我們跟你的兄弟姐妹失聯
We haven't heard anything from your brother or sister
已經有一陣子了
for a while.
我的
My, um...
我的妹妹沒挺過來
My sister didn't make it.
但是  親愛的  我們沒事
But, honey, we're fine.
我們真的沒事
We really are.
我真心希望你也沒事
And I really hope that you are, too.
孩子們
Kids!
過來
Come on out here.
這是拍給爸爸的視頻
It's a tape for dad.
過來  過來問好
Come on. Come. Come say hi.
爸爸  你在哪兒
Daddy, where are you?
我們想你
We miss you.
我們愛你  爸爸
We love you, daddy.
如果可以  就來找我們
Just get here if you can.
我們非常愛你
We love you so much.
好了
Okay. All right.
關掉吧
Let's turn it off.
美國海岸
梅波特海軍基地  佛羅里達
我不知道回家要干嘛
I don't know what we're going home to.
100英里范圍內沒有探測到輻射  長官
No radiation detected within a 100-mile radius, sir.
即使美國遭遇了核襲擊  那也不是這里
If America was nuked, it wasn't here.
我們回家了
We're home.
你說你要不惜一切研發疫苗
You said you have what it takes to make the vaccine.
如果情勢所迫的話  你能在船上研發嗎
If you had to, could you do it here on the ship?
實驗室不是為此目的而建的
The lab wasn't built for that.
只是為了收集數據
It's for collecting data.
但如果不得不那么做  你能嗎
But if you had to, could you?
遠征隊將進行提前部署
The expeditionary team will forward deploy
確保之后的部隊的安全
and secure the area for the next group.
希望我們能夠找到補給
Hopefully we'll find support.
必須做好萬全準備
Got to be prepared for anything.
所有人帶好自己的防化服
Everyone carries their own biohazard suit.
別人不動手我們絕不主動與人交戰
We do not engage unless we are engaged.
讓你們的人準備好  等待新的命令
Prepare your people and await further orders.
解散
Dismissed.
總統依然沒有回復
There's still no answer from POTUS
梅波特還有實驗室那邊都沒消息
and nothing from Mayport or the lab.
我們連無線電調頻信號都收不到
We can't even get an F.M. radio signal.
電網一癱瘓  一切就都癱瘓了
If the power grid's down, that means everything's down.
我們到地面上去的話會知道更多信息
We'll know more when we get boots on the ground.
邁克  我們不回家了
Mike, we're not going home.
這話什么意思
What are you talking about?
實驗室距海岸有200英里
The lab's 200 miles inland.
你也看到新聞了
You saw the news footage.
迫不得已  我們殺也要殺出一條路來
We'll fight our way in there if we have to.
然后呢
And then what?
發電機可能就能用幾周
Generators run out in a couple weeks,
說不定還會有平民想去搶奪
maybe the civilian population tries to overrun it.
變數太大了
There's too many variables.
那我們怎么辦  就待在艦上嗎
So, what do we do? We stay on the ship?
-斯科特博士說這里一應俱全  -又是她
- Dr. Scott says she has what she needs right here. - Dr. Scott.
我們有美國總統
We have standing orders
直接給我們下達的命令啊
from the president of the United States.
那是五天前了
From five days ago.
沒有上級指揮部門的情況下
In the absence of a command structure,
怎樣對我們的任務最有利我說了算
I decide what's in the best interest of our mission.
那我們這里的食物  最多能支撐一周吧
And we have enough food here to last us what, a week?
燃料又有多少
How much fuel?
需要什么我們會找到的
We'll find what we need.
-我們會死在這里的  -不  不會的
- We'll die out there. - No. We will not.
湯姆  你這是好意  我心領了
Tom, I appreciate what you're trying to do.
但是不會成功的  大家都想回家
But it's not gonna work. People want to get home.
那你說讓誰回家
And who exactly gets to go home
我們艦上有216名人員  可只有80套隔離服
when we have 80 biohazard suits for 216 people?
抽簽決定
We draw lots.
我不能這樣做  邁克
I can't think like that, Mike.
這樣至少能給大家一個
It'll at least give people a chance
回家跟親人道別的機會
to get back to their families, to say goodbye.
我不會讓艦上任何人放棄希望的
I'm not letting anybody on this ship give up.
這不是你說了算的  你沒有生殺大權
That's not your call. You don't get to play God.
我仍然是這艘戰艦的艦長
I'm still the captain of this ship.
任務我已經說明了
Now, I've laid out our mission.
希望你服從命令
I expect you to fall in line.
艦長到達艦橋
Captain's on the bridge.
左滿舵  全速前進
Left full rudder. All engines ahead flank.
什么
Sir?
左滿舵
Left full rudder.
全速前進
All engines ahead flank.
收到  左滿舵
Aye, aye. Left full rudder.
全速前進
All engines ahead flank.
左滿舵  全速前進
Left full rudder. All engines ahead flank, aye.
全體人員注意  我是艦長
This is the captain speaking.
我們與總部已經失去聯系
We have no contact with home,
我有理由相信
and I have good reason to believe
美國政府已經垮臺
that the American government is no longer functioning.
我們期望返回的國家已經不復存在
The country we all hoped we were coming back to no longer exists.
四個月前我們作為
We left these shores four months ago
美國海軍  乘艦遠航
as members of the United States navy.
但現在我們不止如此
But now we are more than that.
現在我們肩負著整個世界的命運
Now our duty is to the entire world.
本艦所承載的...
On board this ship is the hope...
是我們的未來  我們的家人
for our futures, for our families,
還有整個人類的希望
and for all of humanity,
因為我們艦上的實驗室里
because in that lab in our helo bay
有結束這場瘟疫的解藥
are the ingredients for a cure.
而現在整個地球上
And this is the safest place on earth
我們的科學家研制解藥最安全的地方
for our scientists to do their work --
就是216名美國海軍所保護的
on a $3 billion piece of machinery
這艘價值30億美元的戰艦
protected by 216 sailors in the U.S. navy.
我們的任務很簡單
Our mission now is simple.
就是竭盡全力在海面上生存下去
We do whatever it takes to stay alive at sea
直到研制出解藥為止
until they find that cure.
關塔那摩灣那邊有一個
There's an unmanned food and fuel station
無人食物燃料供給站
outside Guantanamo Bay.
目前我們的目的地就是那里
For the moment, that is our destination.
我們已經失去了很多
We've lost so much already.
但是本艦所有人員都英勇無畏能屈能伸
But this is the most courageous and resilient crew
我能與大家一起服役是我的榮幸
with whom I have ever been privileged to serve.
所以我們一定可以齊心協力
We will come through this together,
共同度過這個難關
and we will prevail.
繼續前進
Carry on.
所有人員  立正
Attention on deck.
格蘭德森上尉
Lieutenant Granderson,
請求向艦長敬禮
permission to salute the Captain.
請求允許
Permission granted.
舉手敬禮
Hand salute!
代號北極狐  我是海鷗
我不知道該怎么辦了
這艘戰艦不去美國了
我們正在改變航向
末日孤艦
第一季 第一集